Guide to the Raisa Berg Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Correspondence, 1941-2005
  - Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals, 1941-2005
    - Kirpichnikov, Valentin Sergeevich:
      - Berg, Lev to him, 1942 (copy) (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Berg, Raisa, 1941-1952 (mostly Raisa Berg's letters to him) (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - To Aleksandra Vasil'evna, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - To Stalin, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Klebanov, G., St. Louis, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Kleene, Stephen C., Madison, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Kohl, Steve, Washington D.C., 1991 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Kolker, Iurii and Tat'iana, Borehamwood, Leningrad, 1977-2000 (including Tat'iana's poems published in Continent) (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Kolosova, L.R., Novosibirsk, undated, 1971-2003 (Box 9, Folder 9 to 12)
    - Kondrashov, A., Madison, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Kondrat'eva, Liubov' Leont'evna, Moscow, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Kontsevaia-Kol'man, Ekaterina, Stockholm, 1982-1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Korochkin, Leonid Ivanovich, Novosibirsk, 1976-1998 (Box 10, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Korzhavin, Naum Moiseevich, 1975-1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kosovskaia, Esfir' Borisovna, Lincroft, 1986-2002 (see also Sapozhnikova's correspondence) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Kostina, Tat'iana: see Kolker
    - Krass, Polina and Iosif, Carbondale, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Krochik, Gennadii, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Krupitskaia, Natal'ia, Worcester, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Krushinskii, L.V., Moscow, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Kudrina, Kira, various places, 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Kulakov, Mikhail, Rome, 1977-1980 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Kung, Guido, Fribourg, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Kunik, Asia, New York, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Kuznetsov, Grigorii Afanas'evich, Moscow, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Kuznetsova, Liudmila, various places, 1982-1987 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Lande, Russ, Chicago, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Lang, Anton, East Lansing, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Lapo, Andrei Vital'evich, St.Petersburg, 1995-2003 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Laurenson, Anne, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Lax, Renata, Madison, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Layzer, David, Cambridge, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Lebedev, D.V., Leningrad, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Lehrman, Edgar and Ruth, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Lev, A.A., St.Petersburg, 1990-1994 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Levin, Aleksei, New York, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Levin, Evgenii, New York, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Levina, Alla, 19891-1993 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Levit, Georg S., Germany, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Levit, Tilya, New York, 1990-1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Levshin, Aleksei, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Lewis, Virginia, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Lewontin, R.C., 1975 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Liberman, A.S., Minneapolis, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Liebowitz, David N., Atlanta, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Lim, Johng, Eau Claire, 1979-1992 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Litinskii, Vadim, Lakewood, 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Litvinova, L., Moscow, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Liubishchev, A.A., Ul'ianovsk, 1957-1972 (including typescript of his papers presented at the conference in 1927) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Lond, Dmitrii, undated (see related materials in the Paul Feyerabend's correspondence: Box 5, Folder 11) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Longsdon, Pat: see Zaidman
    - Losev, Lev: see Series III: Human Rights Activity--Meilakh (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Loshagin, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Loubens, Tima, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Lowe, David, Bloomington, Nashville, 1979-1986 (Box 11, Folder 4 to 6)
    - Lozanskii, Eduard D., Washington, DC, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Lozner, Lev Gerbertovich, Tiberias, 1979-1981 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Lusis, Ianis Ianovich, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Lusis, Iurii Eduardovich, Washington, DC, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Lynch, Katheryne, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - McCarthy, Ruby "Tess", Madison, Sun Prairie, Tokyo, 1981-1998 (Box 11, Folder 8 to 9)
    - McGrill, Margaret, Seattle, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - MacPeek, Ann, St.Louis, 1988-1990 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Mahanti, Neeti, New Deli, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Makarenko, Mikhail, Munchen, 1979-1983 (including autobiographical note, publication on him, and his writings and publications of 1983) (Box 11, Folder 11 to 12)
    - Makarov, Evgenii and Family, St. Louis, 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Maklina, Moscow, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Maksimov, Nikita, Moscow, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Malakhovskaia, Natal'ia, Austria, 1985-1988 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Maletskii, Stanislav Ignat'evich, Novosibirsk, 1973-2008 (Box 12, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Malinovskii, A.A. (aka Kot), Moscow, 1958-1990 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Malter, Jeffry L., Worcester, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Malygina, Natal'ia Aleksandrovna, Moscow, 1991-1993 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Marcey, David J., Salt Lake City, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Margolis, Doris, Washington, D.C., 1989 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Markovich, Daredjan, France, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Mayr, Ernst, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Mechler, Bernard, undated, 1985-1996 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Medvedev, Zhores, London, undated, 1977-1987 (Box 13, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Medvedeva, I.M., Moscow, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Meilakh, Mikhail and family, Boston, Leningrad, New York, 1975-1999 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Mekler, Iurii, Greenbelt, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Meyer, Helen, Madison, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Miles, Meryl, Madison, 1979 1981 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Minker, Jack, St.Louis, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Mittler, Judieth and Sedney, Dekalb, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Miuge, Sergei: see Mugue
    - Moiseenko, Ekaterina Sergeevna, Moscow, 1940s-1970s (Box 13, Folder 10 to 11)
    - Moore, Carolyn, Richmond Heights, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Morton, Newton E., New York, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Mosolov, Aleksandr Nikolaevich, Novosibirsk, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Mruzik, John, St.Louis, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Mugue, Sergei Georgievich, Jersey City, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Muller, Thea, Bloomington, 1979-1981 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Muller-Hill, Beno, Koln, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Murdachaev, Beatrice, Jackson Heights, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Mutangadura, Tendai, Zimbabwe, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Myrianthopoulos, N.C., 1987 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Narvaez, Veronica, London, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Naumova, Dar'ia, Ul'ianovsk, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Neiding, Veronica, Moscow, 1979-1990 (Box 14, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Neifakh, Aleksandr A., 1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Nikoro, Zoia Sofron'evna, Novosibirs, 1975-1979 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Nissani, Moti, Madison, 1977-2004 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Novitski, E., Eugene, Oregon, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Novozhenov, Iurii I., Ekaterinburg, undated, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Nuller, Iurii, St. Peterburg, 1984-2000 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Ochando, Madrid, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Ohta, Kuniyoshi,, Tokyo, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Omoto, Keiichi, Tokyo, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Onaga, Chris, Lansing, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Opitz, John, Madison, 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Orbeli, Natalia and Garik, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Orlova, Mirra, Brookline, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Orlova-Kopeleva, Raisa, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Panin, Dmitrii, France, 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Panina, Issa Iakovlevna, France, 1985-1988 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Panshin, I.B., Noril'sk, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Panhsina, Irina Borisovna, 1954-1955 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Pardue, may Lou, Cambridge, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Paul, Diana B., Cambridge, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Pavlovskii, Vadim and Ol'ga, 1976-1980 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Pei-Chi Kao, Shanghai, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Pelisson, A., France, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Perlina, Nina, 1975-1981 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Perlovskaia, Ol'ga, 1985-2004 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Perlovskii, Leonid I., 1981-1995 (see also: Vin'kovetskaia, Dina) (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Petrochenkov, Valerii Vasil'evich, 1989-2002 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Petrova, Galina, New York, 1985-1987 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Picard, G., Salt Lace City, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Pirrotta, V., Houston, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Plus, Nadine, France, 1976-1989 (Box 15, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Poliak, Nina, Wilmington, 1983-2004 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Poliakov, Lev E. and Family, New York, 1975-1995 (Box 15, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Polianovskii, Andrei Dmitrievich, St. Petersburg, 1984 (see also: Stark) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Polivanov, Sergei Mikhailovich, Adelphi, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Polivanova, Ol'ga Nikolaevna, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Pomerantseva, Marina Dmitrievna, Moscow, 1988-2004 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Popovskii, Mark Aleksandrovich, New York, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Potter, Van Rensselaer, Madison, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Poulson, Donald F., New Haven, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Pozind, Lev, Jackson Hgts, 1975-1979 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Pribyl, Louis J., Washnigton, D.C., 1982-1984 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Prishepionok, Sergei and E., Portland, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Prokofe'va-Bel'govskaia, A., Moscow, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Raitulis, E., 1990 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Rappoport, Marina, Philadelphia, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Rappoport, Roal'd Iosifovich, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Rapport, Ellen, Toronto, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Rautian, Mariia S., 1977-1998 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Ravdel', E.A., St.Petersburg, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Regel', Elena Dmitrievna, 1983-1991 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Reiter, Hanna, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Reznik, Semen, 1983-2000 (Box 16, Folder 5 to 9)
    - Ritte, Uri, Berkely, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Riveros, Alba Stella, Bogota, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Rodwin, Julie, Cambridge, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Rodwin, Nadine, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Rodwin, Viktor, 1975-1991 (including his articles) (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Roshal', Boris Moiseevich, Kostroma, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Rubin, Gerald M., Baltimore, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Ruffino, Anita, Salisbury Mills, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Rusconi, Ingrid, Rome, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Ruzer, Lev, Tucson, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Sachsse, Walter, 1984-1985 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Saiasova, Vera, 1975-1984 (Box 16, Folder 13 to 14)
    - Sakanian, Nelli, Moscow, undated (see also Babkov correspondence) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Sakharov, Andrei Dmitrievich, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Sapozhnikova, Frida, 1984-1991 (Box 17, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Sariban, Alla, Mainz, undated, 1985-1991 (Box 17, Folder 5 to 12)
    - Savva, Savelii L.: see Zhukoborskii
    - Schindler, Joe and Biene, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Schneider, Laurence A., St. Louis, 1984-1985 (including his paper presented at a conference) (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Schuler, Gerd, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Scudo, Francesco M., 1988-1991 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Sedov, Aleksandr Evgen'evich, Moscow, 1999-2002 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Seligman, Lotti, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Seth, Vinod, New Delhi, undated, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Shainkopf, Selma, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Shandala, Tat'iana, Kyiv, 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Shao Qiquan, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Shapiro, Liudmila, Madison, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Shavrukov, Iurii Nikolaevich, Novosibirsk, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Shmakov, Gennadii, New York, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Shmal'gauzen, I.I., Moscow, 1941-1963 (Box 18, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Shmal'gauzen, O.I., 1966-1968 (Box 18, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Shpitsberg, Natal'ia and Vitalii, St. Louis, 1977-1982 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Shturman, Dora Moiseevna, Jerusalem, 1987-1990 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Shul'kina, T., Chicago, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Shvartsman, Petr, Washington, D.C., 1991-1993 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Simmons, Michael J., St. Paul, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Slavinskii, Efim, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Smakov, Gennady: see Shmakov
    - Smirnov, Leonid Sergeevich, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Sobels, F.H., Leiden, 1975-1984 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Soifer, Valerii and Nina, Columbus, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Solomon, Susan Gross, 1980-1981 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Solov'ev, Sergei, Durham, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Sorokin, Mikhail, New York, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Sosin, Gloria and Gene, White Plains, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Spradling, Allan, Bloomington, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Stark, William S., 1983-1994 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Stein, Hilde, Budenheim, 1984-1991 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Stephan, John J., Honolulu, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Stern, C., Berkeley, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Stierwalt, Bobby, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Superfin, Gabriel, Bremen, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Surikov, Igor' Mikhailovich, Leningrad, 1976-1977 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Suslov, Aleksandr, Silver Spring, 1985-1986 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Susman, Millard, Madison, 1981-1986 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Swafford, Michael, Nashville, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Syed, John, Seattle, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Szyfman, Leon, Gif sur Yvette, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Takhtadzhian, Alisa Grigor'evna i Armen Leonovich, 1990-1992 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Talalai, Mikhail, St. Petersburg, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Tall, Emily, Buffalo, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Tan, C.C., Shanghai, 1981-1982 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Tarshis, Sergei, Leningrad, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Temin, Howard M., Madison, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Temkina, Marina, 1987-1988 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Terry, Dorothy, Labdens, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Thomas, Abigail: see Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Organizations--Liz Darhansoff Literary Agency (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Thomas, Helen, Madison, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Thompson, Margareta, Athens, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Thompson, Vinton, Chicago, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Tiktin, Sergei: see Shturman
    - Torrieri, Mariia, 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Townsend, David R., Chicago, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Tsinker, Grigorii P., Niagara Falls, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Tumerman, Lev Abramovich, Rehovot, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Vakhtin, Iu.B., 2006 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Veenkamp, Jan, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Vekker, Lev, Silver Spring, 1991-1998 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Vin'kovetskaia, Diana, 1976-1999 (Box 19, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Vin'kovetskii, Iakov, 1975-1998 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Volobuev, Vitalii T., 1975-2003 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Volodin, Boris Genrikhovich, Moscow, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Volokhonskii, Anri, Tiberias, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Vorob'ev, Vladimir Iosifovich, Berlin, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Vorontsov, Nikolai N., 1975-1997 (see also: Subseries I.2: correspondence with Organizations--Rossiiskaia akademiia estestvennykh nauk) (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Wald, George, Cambridge, 1975-1985 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Wallace, Bruce, Ithaca, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Wang Xiangming, Wuhan, 1993-1999 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Weiner, Douglas, 1979-1983 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Weingart, Peter, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Wertz, Felitsiia, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - White, Michael J.D., Madison, 1980-1981 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - White, Wade C., Washington, D.C., 1976 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Wild, Maria, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Winbauer, Mary, 2000s (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Wolf, Robert and Myriam, 1975-1988 (see related materials in Subseries 1.2: Correspondence with Organizations--Jewish organizations (Box 24, Folders 4-5) and Series 3: Human Rights Activity--Newsletters) (Box 20, Folder 6 to 8)
    - Womach, Sharon, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Wright, Sewall, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Xin Xiang, Piscataway, 1988-1989 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Yang Long-Chun, Shanghai, 1987-1988 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Yedlin, Bernard S., 1976 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Yoshino, Tatsuji, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Young, Michael W., 1980-1987 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Yurko, Karen, Iowa City, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Zablezhansky, M., undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Zaidman, Anna and Pat, Champaign, 1988-1990 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Zal'tsberg, Mark and family, Houston, 1984-1990 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Zasada, Irenevsz, Denver, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Zel'din, Boris and Sonia, Jersey City, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Zelenko, Grigorii Andreevich, Moscow, 1991 1997 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Zernova, Ruf', Jerusalem, 1991-1997 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Zhukoborskii, Savelii (aka Savva, Savelii L.), Leningrad, 1975-2004 (Box 21, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Ziubina, Liudmila, Kiev, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified, 1975-2003 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Family correspondence (daughters, granddaughters), 1978-2002 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Postcards and greetings, 1977-2003 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Outgoing Correspondence: (Folder 2 to 6)
      - A-W, 1975-1995 (Box 22, Folder 2 to 5)
      - Unidentified, 1976-1994 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Envelopes, undated, 1975-2000 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Subseries I.2: Correspondence with Organizations, 1975-2001
    Comprises correspondence with various organizations, including publishers, universities, magazines, etc. Organized in alphabetical order. (Some correspondence with organizations is a part of personal correspondence and could be found in Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals)
    - ACEP: Program for Soviet Émigré Scholars, 1975-1982 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - American Biographical Institute, 1987-1988 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1980 see Quarterly Review of Biology
    - American Society for Microbiology, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - American Society of Human Genetics, 1985-1992 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Amnesty International, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Association de la Bibliotheque Russe Tourguenev, Paris, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Association for Advancement of the Mentally Handicapped, 1981 (see also: Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Wolf: Box 20, Folders 6-8) (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Congress of the United States. House of Representativse, Washington, D.C.: see Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Kastenmeier (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Conferences, Congresses, Symposiums, undated, 1975-1998
      - Undated, 1975-1982 (Box 22, Folder 12 to 16)
      - 1983-1998 (Box 23, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Dance St. Louis, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Dangers of Apathy, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Department of State, Washington, D.C., 1990-1991 (see also Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Brumberg (Box 3, Folder 8) and Series III: Human Rights Activity-- Letters to political officials: Box 51, Folder 1) (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Dictionnaire du darwinisme et de l'evolution, 1989-1996 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Drosophila Information Service, undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1979-2001 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Genetics Society of Japan, 1981-1996 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Hamburger Stiftung fur Ssozialgeschichte des 20. Jahrhunderts, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Institut fur Humangenetik und Gentische Poliklinik, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Institut fur Sozialfoschung und Entwicklungslehre, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Institut tsitologii i genetiki SOAN SSSR, Novosibirsk, 1991-2000s (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Instituto de Genetica, Universidad de Los Andes, 1987-1989 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Jewish organizations, 1975-1984 (see also Series 3: Human Rights Activity--Newsletters) (Box 24, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Laboratoire de genetique experimentale des populations, Paris, 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Linus Paulin Institute of Science and Medicine, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Literary Agencies: (Folder 7 to 9)
      - Ingrid Schick Authors and Publishers Representative1985-1989 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Liz Darhansoff Literary Agency, 1985-1993 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Mohrbooks, 1989-1990 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Magazines, Almanacs, and Newspapers
      - American Journal of Medical Genetics, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Genetica: see Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Brink, Janny M., van (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Grani, 1984-1985 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Kontinent, 1982-1989 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Nature, 1989-1990 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - Perspectives in Biology and Medicine, Chicago, 1981-1984 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - Russkaia mysl' (materials related to A.Ginzburg): see Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Ginzburg, Aleksandr (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Quarterly Review of Biology, 1979-1990 (see also related materials in Subseries I.2: Correspondence with Individuals--Astaurov: Box 1, Folder 15) (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - Znanie-Sila: see Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Zelenko (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Medizinische Gesellschaft Marburg/Lahn, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - National Cancer Institute, Frederick, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - National Council for Soviet and East European Research, 1979-1992 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - National Institute of Health, Bethesda, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - National Institute of Genetics, Japan, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - National Science Foundation, Washington, D.C., 1981-1983 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Novoe russkoe slovo, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Publishers
      - Albrecht Knaus Verlag, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Chalidze Publications, 1982-2001 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Columbia University Press, 19791984 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Cornell University Press, 1979-1981 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Gordon and Breach, Science Publisheres, Inc., 1985 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Harvard University Press, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Hemann Editeurs des sciences et des arts, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Hermitage, 1984-1992 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Leonard GMBH Edition und Forschung, 1987-1991 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Liepman AG, 1984-1985 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Mosby Times Mirror, 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Nauka, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Oxford University Press, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Pamiatniki istoricheskoi mysli, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Penguin Books Ltd, 1984-1989 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Pergamon Press, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Presses Universitaires de France, 1990-1993 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Princeton University Press, 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Rubatsky, Ken, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - University of California Press, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - University of Chicago Press, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Viking Penguin Inc., 1985-1992 (Box 25, Folder 15 to 17)
      - Vremia i my, 1980-1982 (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - Outgoing, undated, 1982-1992 (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - Envelopes, 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Radio Free Europe; Radio Liberty, 1975 1978 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Slavic Club, Madison, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Slavic Gospel Association, Inc., 1986 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Stadt Mainz, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 2)